<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edible Campus</title>
    <description>Edible gardens at UC Davis.
</description>
    <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 17:39:10 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 17:39:10 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kansas City Food Scraps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My grandmother was composting before ‘sustainability’ held international weight. Her fascination with her Kansas City food scraps was - despite her archetypal grandma kookiness- nothing short of visionary. Her sloping, Bermuda Grass backyard was renovated with 3 raised beds in 2004, back when I, a 9 year-old tallboy, was infatuated with dirt. Back before I knew to distinguish dirt from soil, and gave onions not a second’s thought. My grandmother’s garden was the first one I met; it was a corn-belt soliloquy, iridescent in the springtime sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is clearly congregative. It’s a cosmic simplicity, satiating our gurgly bellies. Though, our palettes have adjusted to expect french fries over potatoes. These simple artificial transformations have split us farther from our food, consequently, farther from our soils. The complexities of today’s food system have trained us to leapfrog parts of commodity chains, making less out of more. We now anticipate the conclusive, processed versions of the same foods originating in our backyard gardens; raw has turned refined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enact change is no dainty feat, and a small garden is hardly enough for a head-nod of approval in our global food system. Regardless, real change is most positive when comprised of of passion-fueled, small but mighty little guys. The Salad Bowl Garden is one of those little guys, growing veggies for public consumption. Plants produced by the people for the people. 100% of what’s grown is for the taking, and the cleverly situated garden site stands valiantly as both a placeholder and a production zone. Nestled smack-dab in the PES (Plant and Environmental Sciences) courtyard, the Salad Bowl Garden is equal parts aesthetics and exposure. After all, what is an ag. school experience if swiss chard and peppers aren’t beckoning for your harvest as you leave class? The power in a garden is its direct path to the kitchen table from the soil. There is no processing or unnecessary additives. That swiss chard and those peppers are turned to salad, stuffed pies, chili pastes and stir fries. Not only does it encourage healthy eating, it exposes students to the kitchen, to turning what they can find outside into what they can fill their bodies with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, more than anything else, is my grandmother’s mission statement. To turn soil to sustenance, with cooking snuggled in between. To engage young and old in the collaboration that is edible spaces, and to produce, engage and enthuse the public in a movement towards playing a more congregative, cognizant and devoted role in our food system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/blog/2016/05/12/tbd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/blog/2016/05/12/tbd/</guid>
        
        <category>Salad</category>
        
        <category>Bowl</category>
        
        <category>Garden</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EC Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASUCD Experimental Community Gardens (ECG) are an inclusive space for people to learn about sustainable gardening, enhance health and well‐being, engage in experiential learning, connect with the community, and practice environmental stewardship. Gardeners grow nourishing food, learn together, and develop lasting friendships. A unit within the Associated Students of the University of California, Davis (ASUCD), the ECG occupy five acres of organic farmland between the Domes and the Student Farm Market Garden. Plots are available for rent on an annual basis to students, faculty, staff and community members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For information about the ECG or to rent a plot, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ecgardenwebsite.wix.com/ecgarden&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/ec</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/ec</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>College Celebration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 04:25:17 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/events/2015/11/23/news-article/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/events/2015/11/23/news-article/</guid>
        
        <category>Apple</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salad Bowl Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Started in 2008, the Salad Bowl Garden is run by students and eaten by anyone. Situated just outside the Plant and Environmental Sciences building, the Salad Bowl Garden is an interactive edible landscape where you can pick your salad and eat fresh food while at school or work. A range of crops are grown to meet staff and student preferences, be eaten raw, and follow healthy agronomic practices. Check out the garden signs to learn about vegetable varieties, water-saving irrigation techniques, organic fertilization methods, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each quarter, the garden team hosts salad bowl lunches, where all are invited to harvest and enjoy their own salads. Additionally, all members of the UC Davis community are welcome to visit the garden at any time and harvest as they please! Stop by the Salad Bowl Garden on Picnic Day - April 16, 2016 - for fun activities put on by students in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arboretum.ucdavis.edu/student_opportunities.aspx&quot;&gt;Arboretum and Public Garden’s Edible Landscaping Internship.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/sbg</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/sbg</guid>
        
        <category>feature</category>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Edible Landscaping Internship Greenhouse</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student interns of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arboretum.ucdavis.edu/student_opportunities.aspx&quot;&gt;Edible Landscaping Internship&lt;/a&gt; propagate plants for several edible landscapes on campus and for Arboretum plant sales. Currently, these edible plants are propagated at the Environmental Horticulture greenhouses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get involved propagating edible plants through the Arboretum and Public Garden’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://arboretum.ucdavis.edu/student_opportunities.aspx&quot;&gt;Edible Landscaping Internship&lt;/a&gt;, by attending workdays or applying to be an intern.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/elig</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/elig</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UC Davis Apple Harvest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/events/2015/09/22/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/events/2015/09/22/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        <category>Apple</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Viticulture &amp; Enology Teaching Vineyard</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UC Davis Viticulture and Enology program planted a vineyard adjacent to the Robert Mondavi Institute for Wine and Food Science in 2011. The teaching vineyard features varieties from all over the world and is intended to provide hands-on learning for Viticulture and Enology students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RMI vineyard is for use by Viticulture and Enology students, faculty, and staff. To learn more, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wineserver.ucdavis.edu/about/facilities/vineyards/Campus%20Vineyards.html&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/viticulture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/viticulture</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Horticulture Innovation Lab Demonstration Center</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;h2&gt;

The Horticulture Innovation Lab demonstration center, started in 2015, seeks to share innovative technologies and practices with colleagues visiting from around the country and the world. It is an active site for students, faculty, and staff to test new horticultural tools and demonstrate best practices for growing fruits and vegetables — particularly those helpful to small-scale farmers in developing countries. The demonstration center is spearheaded by Horticulture Innovation Lab and is also part of the UC Davis GATEways Project, a campuswide initiative developed by the UC Davis Arboretum and Public Garden to showcase the academic strengths of UC Davis, inspire life-long learning, and engage with the local community.

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;h2&gt;

To learn more about the demonstration center, visit the Horticulture Innovation Lab [website](http://horticulture.ucdavis.edu/main/center_ucdavis.html) and check out the [blog](http://blog.horticulture.ucdavis.edu/2015/06/our-newest-center-here-at-uc-davis/).

&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/horticulture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/horticulture</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Biological Orchard and Gardens (BOG)</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Biological Orchard and Gardens (BOG) is a collaboration between students, staff, and faculty to convert an underutilized landscape in the heart of campus into a living museum which showcase permaculture practices and biodiversity. A quarter of the space will feature a first-of-its-kind orchard of heirloom California fruit trees threatened with extinction. Once it is established, visitors to the garden are free to sample the harvests. The remaining space will feature drought-tolerant plants native to South Africa, the Mediterranean, and California, serving as an outdoor ecological classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the BOG on Facebook: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/ucdBOG&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/ucdBOG&lt;/a&gt;. To join the BOG team as an intern, volunteer, or supporter, leave a message on Facebook, or contact Student Project Manager Emily Dorrance at &lt;a href=&quot;eadorrance@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;eadorrance@ucdavis.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/bog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/bog</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Student Health and Wellness Center Gardens</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;h2&gt;

Outside the Student Health and Wellness Center is a welcoming landscape home to many edible plants. The organically grown Harvest Garden Gardeners offers visitors an opportunity to learn about the benefits of growing and eating fresh fruit and vegetables. Cared for by Health Education and Promotion student staff and volunteers, it serves as a demonstration space for teaching about edible gardening.

The Healing Patch is a medicinal garden incorporated into the landscape just south of the building. Visit the Healing Patch to learn more about medicinal and ethnobotanical uses of plants and to gain inspiration to incorporate medicinals into your own garden.

&lt;h2&gt;Get Involved&lt;h2&gt;

Check out the Student Health and Counseling Services [blog](https://shcs.ucdavis.edu/blog/) for updates.

&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/studenthealth</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ediblecampus.ucdavis.edu/gardens/studenthealth</guid>
        
        
        <category>garden</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
